(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T05:39:49.715211",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
お肉食べよう！
Let's eat meat!
お肉 肉 肉 肉 肉 肉 肉食べたい！
Want to eat meat, meat, meat!
お肉食べたい！
Want to eat meat!
お肉 お肉 お肉 お肉 お肉 お肉 食べよう
Meat, meat, meat, let's eat meat!
元気お肉 お肉
Energetic meat, meat,
頬っぺたうるうる
Cheeks all glossy and dewy!
お肉 お肉 お肉 お肉食べよう
Meat, meat, meat, let's eat meat!
まんまるおだんご まんまるおだんご かわいい仲間
Round dumplings, round dumplings, cute friends!
タレ タレ タレ付きに
With plenty of sauce,
煮ても焼いても揚げても
whether boiled, grilled, or fried—
あなた好みになるのよ
it becomes just how you like it!
ナルノヨ~
(Just how you like it~)
お鍋 おべんと
Hot pot, bento boxes,
パーティ
parties!
今日は何？何？何？何！何！何！何！何！
What is it today? What, what, what, what!
肉と肉とで 肉だんご
Meat plus meat equals meatball!
オー肉 お肉お肉 お肉お肉 お肉お肉お肉お肉
Oh, meat, meat, meat, meat, meat, meat!
みんなしあわせ
Everyone is happy,
肉でニコリ
smiling with meat!
世界が笑顔いっぱいに
Filling the world with smiles—
サンキュー お肉
Thank you, meat!
ありがとう~
Thank you~
おにくじゃぽねすく！
Oniku Japonesque!
国産のお肉
Domestic meat,
domestic meat!
肉 肉
Meat, meat,
じゃぽねすく！
Japonesque!
飛んできて とりあえずギュッてしててば
Fly over and just squeeze me tight—
ささみなことはスネちゃうなんて初恋かしらって
pouting over trivial things, is this first love?
アキレステール ウィンナにははむかうつもり
Intending to bite back at Achilles tendon wieners!
アイビキしたら ハラミでステーキ
After minced meat, skirt steak!
国産のおにく
Domestic meat,
domestic meat!
にっくにくにっく！ ジャポネスク！
Meat, meat, meat! Japonesque!
トンできて とりあえず ギューってして テバ！
Fly over and give a hug for now, chicken wings!
ササミなことで スネちゃうなんて はつ恋カシラ
Pouting over a tenderloin, must be first love.
アキレステール ウインナには ハムここうつ
Achilles' heel, wieners, and ham croquettes.
アイビキしたら ハラミて！ステーキ
If you do a mincemeat mix, skirt steak! Steak!
にくるしい あなた なぜか 今日は ふさぎ顔
Meat-sick, why are you wearing a gloomy face today?
きっと あれかしら たんぱく質が 足りないのね
Must be that you're lacking in protein.
ミーとユーとの ジューシーなおにく
Juicy meat between me and you!
ユートミーとの げんきな えい！えい！おう！
An energetic "Ei! Ei! Oh!" between you and me!
ミーとユーとの ジューシーなおにく
Juicy meat between me and you!
ユートミーとの ハッピーなおにく
Happy meat between you and me!
だあいすき！ 国産のおにく
I love you so much! Domestic meat!
国産のおにく
Domestic meat,
domestic meat!
にっくにくにっく！
Meat, meat, meat!
ジャポネスク！
Japonesque!
だあいすきよ あなたと1つになれるのなら
I love you so much, if I could become one with you,
こんな幸せはないわ
there's no greater happiness than this...
お味はいかが？
How does it taste?
ロースも スキヤキな 恋がミノ・レバ
Roast and sukiyaki romance is sweetbread and liver,
モツも つみだ モモいろは 一とバラ ほろヒレはれ
motsuten, peach color, ribs, melting fillet.
ウシ・リブ ゆびサガリ てってけ いかん センマイ
Beef rib, finger hanging, tendon, omasum.
ギアらな タンなら おなかぺこ ペーコン
Tongue if you like, hungry belly bacon.
にくるしい あなた つるり 今日は タマゴ肌
Meat-sick, you have smooth egg-like skin today.
たぷん あれだわ 野菜もいっぱい 食べたのね
Must be why you ate lots of vegetables too.
ミーとユーとの ジューシーなおにく
Juicy meat between me and you!
ユートミーとの しょうょく わくわくおう！
An exciting appetite between you and me!
ミーとユーとの ジューシーなおにく
Juicy meat between me and you!
ユートミーとの ハッピーなおにく
Happy meat between you and me!
だあいすき！
I love you so much!
国産のおにく
Domestic meat,
domestic meat!
にっくにくにっく！
Meat, meat, meat!
ジャポネスク！
Japonesque!
だあいすきよ あなたと1つになれるのなら
I love you so much, if I could become one with you,
もっともっとあたしを愛して
love me more and more!
だあいすきよ
I love you so much,
あなたと1つになれるのなら
if I could become one with you,
こんな幸せはないわ…
there's no greater happiness than this...
お味はいかが？
How does it taste?
ということで、やってきました！白銀ノエル生誕祭2023！
And so, it's finally here! Shirogane Noel's Birthday Celebration 2023!
イェーイ！おめでとう！ありがとう！
Yay! Happy birthday! Thank you!
はい、ということで改めまして司会を務めさせていただきます。鼻声の天音かなたです！
Yes, so once again, I'll be serving as your MC. I'm Amane Kanata with a stuffy nose!
大丈夫だよ！鼻声ですが大丈夫です。
It's okay! Even with a stuffy nose, it's fine.
そして、本日の主役の！わーい！どうも主役です、誕生日です！ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです！
And now, today's guest of honor! Yay! Hello, I'm the star, it's my birthday! I'm Shirogane Noel from Hololive 3rd Gen!
はい、そしてお馴染みのね、豪華ゲストの皆さんでございます。はーい！
Yes, and here are our familiar, gorgeous guests. Yay!
こんぬに！え、豪華ゲストのひとり、え、ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアです！
Hello! I'm one of the gorgeous guests, Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Generation!
ぺこーら！豪華ゲストのひとりのうさぎ、うさだぺこらぺこー！
Peko-la! One of the gorgeous guests, Usada Pekora-peko!
同じく豪華ゲストのひとり、宝鐘マリンです！わあー！
Also one of the gorgeous guests, Houshou Marine! Yay!
はい、ということでね、今日は、え、団長が誕生日祝いに牛丼を振る舞ってくれるというね、話で皆さん呼ばれていたと思うんですけど…
Yes, so today, I think you were all invited under the premise that Danchou would treat us to gyudon for her birthday...
まあ、なんでかネ、あの、関係のない僕が司会を務めさせてもらっております。
But for some reason, unrelated old me is serving as the MC here.
いや、だっていや司会と言ったらかなたんっしょゅね！
Well, I mean, when you say MC, you think of Kanatan, right?!
いやありがと…ありがたいよ、鼻声だけどね。ちょっと今日は鼻声だけど、あと皆さんちょっと気づきませんか？クイズ番組っぽい…
Well, thanks... I appreciate it, even with my stuffy nose. Though my voice is stuffed today... Also, don't you guys notice something? It looks like a quiz show...
確かに、何だこれ、不穏だなこれ。なんか、これ牛丼食べるだけって感じじゃない…
True, what is this, it's ominous. It doesn't feel like we're just here to eat gyudon...
いやー、まあまあまあ、ちょっと皆さんとりあえず落ち着いてもらっていいっすか？えっと、今日、ま、今日はね、あの、団長と、まあ、一緒にね、こうやって誕生日だからわーって食べていただく感じ、だったんすけども…
Well, well, well, could everyone calm down for a second? Today, well, today, Danchou and everyone were supposed to celebrate together and go "Yay!" and eat... but...
なんか、ね、ちょっと、準備が楽しすぎて…ということで、ま、団長、あの、究極の…
Somehow, y'know, preparation was too much fun... And so, Danchou, um, the ultimate...
究極牛丼をつくる旅にでて、きた!
I've set out on a journey to make the ultimate gyudon!
いつの間に旅です？
When did you go on a journey?
究極牛丼！？
The ultimate gyudon?!
なんですかそれは！出てきました！
What is that?! It came out!
まあ、ちょっとね、ここら辺の雛壇とかは置いといて、とりあえずVTRどうぞ！
Well, let's put the commentary dais aside for now, and here's the VTR!
なんて？VTR！？何？どうぞ行くやん！
What? A VTR?! What? Go ahead!
白銀ノエルにとって“牛丼”とは？
What does "gyudon" mean to Shirogane Noel?
牛丼、それは団長にとっての完全食なんです
Gyudon... To the Captain, it's the ultimate complete meal!
完全食の理由は、みなさんお分かり、めちゃめちゃ美味しいから。
The reason it's a complete meal is, as you all know... because it's super delicious!
誕生日も来ますし、ずっと叶えたかった夢を、団長叶えようと思うんです。
My birthday is coming up, and I want to fulfill a dream I've always had, Captain.
究極の牛丼を作るという夢
The dream of making the ultimate gyudon!
牛丼において大事なのは...
What's important in gyudon is...
肉、玉ねぎ。
Meat and onions.
この2つの食材は特に重要っすよね。
These two ingredients are especially important, right?
いや～これは行くしかない、やるしかない！
Man... we have to go, we have to do this!
白銀ノエル、究極牛丼を作る旅に出やす！
Shirogane Noel, setting out on a journey to make the ultimate gyudon!
しっけい、しっけい、行ってきやす！
Pardon me, pardon me, I'm heading out!
牛丼大好き❤️
I love gyudon!
ノエ旅あびゃや！全国おいしい発見！～高級食材で牛丼づくりに挑む～
Noe-tabi Abyaya! Delicious Discoveries Across Japan! ～Challenging Gyudon Making with Luxury Ingredients～
みなさん、こんまっする！
Everyone, kon-muscle!
牛丼ハンター白銀ノエルこと団長白銀ノエルです！
Gyudon Hunter Shirogane Noel, Captain Shirogane Noel!
やってきました兵庫県神戸市内！
We've come to Kobe City, Hyogo Prefecture!
こちら神戸大橋です！
This is the Kobe Ohashi Bridge!
でけ～！風つえ～！
Huge~! So windy~!
団長のお目当てはここ神戸にあります。
The Captain's target is right here in Kobe.
神戸のお肉と言ったら？
When you think of Kobe meat...
神戸牛！
Kobe beef!
そう、神戸牛！
That's right, Kobe beef!
まずは神戸牛をゲットしに行きます！
First, we're going to get some Kobe beef!
うお～！
Whoa~!
1854年開国、1868年神戸港開港。
Opening of the country in 1854, Kobe Port opened in 1868.
食肉文化が発展し、神戸牛やブランド牛は世界に名を響かせてきました。
Meat culture developed, and Kobe beef and brand beef became known worldwide.
しかしみなさんはご存知だろうか、そのブランド牛の始祖となる牛が兵庫から生まれていたこと！
But did you know that the ancestor of those brand beefs originated in Hyogo?
その牛の名は――
The name of that cattle is—
但馬牛
Tajima cattle.
但馬牛を求めとある牧場へ。
Seeking Tajima cattle, heading to a certain ranch.
ここが兵庫か！空が青い！山がデカイ！
So this is Hyogo! The blue sky! The huge mountains!
すごい大自然を感じま... ちょっと待ってください。
Feeling the great nature... Wait a minute.
今、地面が揺れた？
Just now, did the ground shake?
これは600キロの波動がいくつも連なったものです。
This is a series of 600-kilogram shockwaves combined.
今、風の知らせで牧草の香りがします。
Right now, on the wind's notice, I smell pasture grass.
牧草そして600キロの波動、これはA5ランクの神戸牛が近くにいる、つまり団長が探している但馬牛がいる！
Pasture and 600kg shockwaves... This means A5 rank Kobe beef is nearby, meaning the Tajima cattle the Captain is looking for is here!
じゃあ、ここら辺を重点的に探索してみましょう、行ってきます！
Well then, let's search around here intensively, here I go!
何かここら辺にA5ランクのいい牛さんがいるような匂いがしますね。
I feel like there's a good scent of A5 rank cows around here.
すみま～せん、こんにちは！
Excuse meee, hello!
もしかしてこの牛さんたちは全て...？
Could these cows all be...?
ここにいるのは全部メスの但馬牛になります。
The ones here are all female Tajima cattle.
小柄で骨が細く身体の締まりが良いため良好な筋繊維を持つ。
Small-framed with fine bones and a tight body, they have good muscle fibers.
団長のことを見つめてます。もしかしたら団長のことが好きかもしれないんで...
She's staring right at the Captain. Maybe she likes the Captain...
触れ合ってみたいと思います。
Let's try interacting with her.
ふふふ、うわ！笑い方、キモいよ！
Fufufu, whoa! That laugh is creepy!
団長の手をペロペロしてくれました！すごく生温かいです。
She licked the Captain's hand! It's so lukewarm.
これが美味しいタンになるんだね、ありがとね。
So this becomes delicious tongue, thank you.
A5ランクの神戸牛候補生ってことですよね。
So these are A5 rank Kobe beef candidates, right?
厳しい審査を通過した但馬牛が神戸ビーフとなります。
Tajima cattle that pass strict evaluations become Kobe Beef.
実は神戸牛という品種は存在せず、厳しい評価基準をクリアした特別な但馬牛が神戸牛と名乗ることを許されているのです。
Actually, the breed "Kobe Beef" does not exist; only special Tajima cattle that clear strict evaluation criteria are allowed to call themselves Kobe Beef.
日本が誇るブランド、松坂牛、近江牛、米沢牛、宮崎牛、仙台牛など、
Brands Japan boasts: Matsusaka beef, Omi beef, Yonezawa beef, Miyazaki beef, Sendai beef, etc.
そのルーツのほとんどが但馬牛であり、全国の黒毛和牛の99.9%が但馬牛の血を引いている。
Most of their roots are Tajima cattle, and 99.9% of Black Wagyu cattle nationwide carry Tajima cattle blood.
黒毛和牛の99.9%が
99.9% of Japanese Black cattle
但馬牛の血を引いている。
trace their lineage back to Tajiri-go,
但馬牛という品種を生んだ田尻号という牛なのですが、
the bull that established the breed.
それではこの牛舎の前で、
So, in front of this cattle barn...
クエスチョンです。
Question!
Q.田尻号は生涯で何頭の子孫を残した？
How many descendants did Tajiri-go leave in his lifetime?
わかるかな～？
Can you guess?
という ことでですね、この問題も含めて、
So, including this question,
これから計3問ほどクイズが出ます皆さん！
we'll have a total of 3 quiz questions!
1問正解できたら1ptゲットで、
If you get 1 right, you get 1 point.
合計5ptゲットできたら牛丼を食べる権利が与えられますが、
If you get a total of 5 points, you get the right to eat gyudon...
なんか おかしくね？
Wait, something's off, right?
賢い皆さんはすぐに分かる、
You should know right away!
えー、クイズの数と合計ポイントが合っていませんよね。
The number of quizzes and total points don't match!
皆さんには予め2体の団員さんが与えられております！
You've been given 2 Danchou-san mascots in advance!
あ！団員さん出てきた！よきよき！
Danchou-san!
クイズの回答に自信がありましたら、団員さんをマックス2体までBET、賭けることができます！
You can bet up to 2 Danchou-san mascots if you're confident in your answer!
そして賭けて正解した場合1体につき2倍のポイントがゲットできます！
If you bet and get it right, you get double points per mascot!
団員さんは使い回しでまたBET出来るわけではないので使いどころは要検討！
You can't reuse Danchou-san for multiple bets, so timing is crucial!
ここぞ！絶対当てるっていうときにぜひね、使ってみてくださいという感じで、
Use them when you're 100% sure you'll win.
不正解の場合はBETしたその団員さんの数だけ没収となります！
If you're wrong, you lose as many Danchou-san as you bet!
なくなりますからそこから消えます。
You'll lose them, so be careful!
はい、一旦団員さんは引っ込んじゃおうね。
Say goodbye, Danchou-san!
バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
団員さんをBETしたい方は回答後にBETするか否かを教えてください。
Let us know if you want to bet after answering!
5ポイントゲットを目指して頑張りましょう！
Let's aim for 5 points!
はい、頑張りまーす！やったー！
Yeah, let's do our best!
ちなみに司会の僕はクイズしなくても食べられますよね？牛丼。
Wait, as the host, I get to eat gyudon without doing the quiz, right?
いや、そりゃ もちろん！
Well, of course!
お前聞いてるんだろ答え！なんで参加してんだよ！
Wait, why are you participating?!
だってさ、こっちの方が楽しそうだって思ったんだもん！答えさせろや！
I thought it'd be more fun, so let me answer!
全問正解は当たり前だよね、長官はね、そうなると。
Of course, you'd get a full score, right?
まぁでも5点目指すのも楽しそうだ な、と。
Well, aiming for 5 points is fun too.
ということでね、ルール説明もできましたので、早速回答記入タイムに入ります！
Now, let's get into the answer writing time!
なんだっけ？
Wait, what was the question?
比尻号が分かんない。
I don't get Tajiri-go.
なんだっけ？話、子孫、子孫。
What was the story? Descendants?
田尻号は13年間で何頭の子孫を残した？13年だよ。13年ね！
Tajiri-go left how many descendants in 13 years? 13 years!
ちなみに田尻号はですね、オスの牛さん、雄牛でございますから、
Tajiri-go was a male bull, so...
あー！仕込むってことね！
Ah, breeding!
和牛の偉大な父と呼ばれている。
He's called the great father of Wagyu beef.
13年の間で何頭の子孫を残したかということです から、みなさんどうでしょうか？
So how many descendants did he leave in those 13 years?
いや～たくさんいてほしいなぁ～、どういう感想ぺこだよ…ワクワク。
I want there to be a lot... But how many could there be?
皆さん、記入はどうですか？できましたか？
Everyone, are you done writing?
できました！おねがいしまーす！
Yes!
それでは皆さん記入できたようなので、じゃあまず長官以外の3人の回答を見ていきましょう。
Alright, everyone's done, so let's start with the non-choukan answers.
では一斉に表示していきましょう！どうぞ！
Let's reveal them all at once! Ready?
これ！何？無限？バカじゃねえの！
What, infinity?
数えられるわけねーじゃん！基本にさ、13年間でもう終わってんの！
You can't even count them! 13 years is already over!
確かに！待って、確かに。
Wait, that's true...
数えられるわけねーじゃん！どこで生んでるかも分かんないとこだってあるかもしれないじゃん！
You can't count them! There might even be places we don't know about!
じゃあね、フレアの回答からちょっと見ていきましょう。120ということで、
Well, Flare's answer is 120.
希望的観測を込めたんだけど、少なかったかもしれない。120くらいかなと自信ありますか？
I added some hopeful thinking, but maybe it was less. Are you confident in 120?
全然ないです。
Not at all!
じゃあ これば、団員さんBETは…
And your Danchou-san bet is...
1000！1000！
1000!
せんかん！
なるほど。
I see.
それでは次は無限大のぺこら先輩！
Next is the infinite Pekora-senpai!
だってお牛さんで、一頭のさ、誰と誰みたいな…
Because, you know, bulls and... who and who...
たじりごうさんでしたっけ？
Was it Tajiri-go?
いくつもの雌牛といろいろやってるかもしれないけど
You might have been with all sorts of cows, but...
数えられるわけ無くね？普通に
There's no way you can count that, right? Obviously.
ちゅうことは無限しかないの！誰も数えられないからじゃあ無限にしましょうか？
That means it's infinite! Nobody can count them, so let's just make it infinite, right?
お前団員賭けろもうそれ！
Bet your officers on that already!
いくしかない！
You gotta go!
団員賭けよう！賭ける？
Let's bet the officers! Bet 'em?
わかったよ…団員…
Fine... my officers...
おっ！団員MAX2！いくー！
Oh! Officer MAX 2! Let's go!
いくしかないよ！いくしかない！
You gotta go! You gotta go!
こいつら賭けて！で、賭ける2なんだよね、正解したら
Put these guys down! And it's times 2 if you get it right, right?
そうですよ。
That's right.
よし！無限！じゃあ行きましょうか！
Alright! Infinite! Then let's go!
それではあとマリンね、マリンの回答は
Next is Marine. Marine's answer...
え、マリンの回答これね、ちょっとパッと見380頭に見えるんですけど、これよくよく見ると無限なんですね。
At a glance it looks like 380 head, but if you look closely, it's actually infinite.
380の8のところが、段々無限になっていって、380の8の部分は
The 8 in 380 gradually turns into infinity, and the 8 part of 380 is...
ちょっと自分の年齢の話で、380の部分で、なんで380かじゃないの、なんで380の80にしちゃったの？
It's about my age... Why 380? Why did I make it 380?
え、これは、えっと、13、ちょっと待って！ちょっと待って！そんなこと一日中考えてるんじゃないでしょ？ 80にするか、50にするか？
Um, this is, um, 13—wait a second! Wait a second! You're not thinking about stuff like that all day long, are you?
し、静かに。
Shh, quietly.
お前もBETするんだよなペコラに。
You're gonna bet too, right, Pekora?
これじゃBETしますか？お前BETするよな？
So you're gonna bet? You're gonna bet, right!?
80頭でBET！するよな！？
Betting 80 head! You're gonna do it!?
いやもう一旦いいか、一旦。
Well, whatever, for now...
ええんだよ！一旦いいか、いやBETはしないということで。最初の問題でいきなりBETするやつってバカじゃん！
It's fine! Whatever, so I'm not betting. Anyone who bets right off the bat on the first question is an idiot!
2匹！復活できたんだよ！うわけねえだろ！2匹使ってでもマックスなんだよ、こいつらで。
Two! We were able to revive them! No way! Even using two, that's the max for these guys.
でも自信あるんでしょ？
But you're confident, right?
まぁ自信あるわ。
Well, I'm confident.
自信あるわ。
Confident.
ありえねえな。全然。
No way. Not at all.
じゃあいいじゃん。
Then it's fine.
いいじゃんいいじゃん。なるほどなるほど。
It's fine, it's fine. I see, I see.
じゃあまあ皆さん最後に、えー団長の答えを見ていきましょうか。
Well then everyone, finally, let's look at the Dancho's answer.
では団長の答えはこちら！
Now, the Dancho's answer is right here!
はい！なんだ？な、なんだこれ。何これ文字でかすぎ。肉おいしい！ 290141頭！！ノエル
Ta-da! What is this? What is this? Why is the text so huge? Delicious meat! 29,0141 head!! Noel
いやもうぽけーと
Well, I was just spacing out...
ああ、でかい！でかい！でかい！大体でかい。
Ah, huge! Huge! Huge! Mostly huge.
マジで！もう文字でかすぎてもうこのね、完璧な牛丼の絵でなんかどうにか、もう肉の熱量が、でもねちょっときっ、なんかちょっとねこの、これに関しては
Seriously! The text is so huge, trying to make do with this picture of a perfect gyudon, the passion for meat—but you know, regarding this...
団長ね答え知らない！知らないのかよ！
Dancho doesn't know the answer! You don't know?!
知らないの？え、聞いてないの？
You don't know? Eh, you didn't hear?
聞き手もするお。あ、そういうパターンもあるんだ。
There's that kind of pattern too, huh.
そういうパターンもあるんですよ。なのでちょっとこれが、いいか、なんかみたいな回答なんですよね。
There's that kind of pattern too. So that's why this is... kind of answer.
あれ？てか、ちなみになんですけど団長、BETはしますか？団員さん。
Huh? By the way, Dancho, are you going to bet? Your officers?
でも団員さんの顔見たい！からちょっと
But I want to see my officers' faces! So just...
はい、あの1匹ちょっと見たいな。
Yeah, I'd like to see one of them.
1匹だよこれ。
Just one, huh.
じゃあ1匹BET。最高じゃん！やだ、お別れだね。ハッピー！
Then 1-pet bet. Awesome! Oh no, it's time to part. Happy!
さあ、それでは皆さんこの中に正解した方はいらっしゃるんでしょうか！？頼む！
Now then, is there anyone here who got it right?! Please!
それでは正解を発表します。こちらです！
Now we will announce the correct answer. Here it is!
13年間でなんと！約1500頭！
In 13 years, believe it or not! About 1,500 head!
なるほど。持ったんだけどな。なんで気づけなかったんだ。
I see. I had it. Why couldn't I realize it.
半分じゃん、っていうことでね。
It's half, you could say.
ま、こうしてね、あの、今現在日本で純血種の黒毛和牛が美味しく食べられるのも、この田尻号が自然交配でなんと1500頭ほど…子孫を残してくれたというね。
Well, like this, um, the reason we can currently eat purebred Kuroge Wagyu deliciously in Japan is because this Tajiri-go left behind about 1,500 offspring through natural mating.
子孫を残してくれたということでね、ありがとうございます。
Leaving behind offspring, thank you very much.
本当に。無限？いや無限！
Seriously. Infinite? No, infinite!
なんでバカなの、バカバカ！
Why are you stupid, stupid stupid!
いや無限おかしくない？数えられない、大体約でしょ。
Isn't infinite weird? You can't count it, it's roughly 'about'.
約1500だよ？そんな細かく書いてないっちゅうことは無限と同じじゃないですか！
It's about 1,500, you know? Not writing it in detail means it's the same as infinite!
いやちょっとね、司会者権限でどうぺこですかこれ。
Hold on, how about this by host authority?
あ、残念ながら！ダメがダメがダメが！
Ah, unfortunately! No no no!
お別れだよ、お別れだよ。没収されますよ。
Time to say goodbye, goodbye. It's getting confiscated.
思考放棄、思考放棄～。
Mind empty, mind empty~.
380だってそんなの適当だろ！違うじゃん！
380 was just a guess! That's wrong!
全員不正解、0ポイントで～す！
Everyone is incorrect, 0 points!
没収しないで！没収しないで！
Don't confiscate! Don't confiscate!
ということでですね、不正解だったぺこら先輩、そしてノエル団長の団員は没収！
And so, Pekora-senpai and Noel-dancho's officers who got it wrong are confiscated!
バイバーイ！さよなら！
Bye-bye! Goodbye!
狩り。バイバーイ！さよなら！
Captured. Bye-bye! Goodbye!
まだまだ挽回のチャンス皆様ありますから、引き続き諦めずに頑張っていきましょう！
You all still have a chance for a comeback, so keep doing your best without giving up!
それではVTRの続きをどうぞー！
Now then, please enjoy the rest of the VTR!
牛丼ハンターノエルは、田尻牛の肉質を見極めるため川岸牧場の直営精肉店、肉処樹さんへと向かいました。
Gyudon Hunter Noel headed to Niku-dokoro Tatsuki, a direct-managed butcher shop of Kawaishi Ranch, to assess the meat quality of Tajiri beef.
今から商肉を食肉にする作業をご覧いただければと思います。
Now we will show you the process of turning commercial meat into edible cuts.
ぜひ見たいです。よろしくお願いします。
I'd love to see it. Thank you very much.
お～
Whoa.
すっごい！
Amazing!
分厚いお肉がどんどん切られてます。
Thick cuts of meat are being sliced up.
脂身を削って、どんどん滑らかになってる。
Trimming the fat, it's becoming smoother and smoother.
これがプロの手さばき。
This is professional knife work.
断面図！すごいサシ。
Cross-section! Look at that amazing marbling.
このサシの良さがあります。
Look at this beautiful marbling.
しなやかで締まりの良い筋肉が良質な脂肪を内面に留まらせて生まれるこの美しいサシが生まれるのです。
This gorgeous marbling is created when firm, supple muscles retain high-quality fat within.
牛丼ハンター白銀ノエル あとは部位を決めるのみ！
Gyudon Hunter Shirogane Noel, now it's time to choose the cut!
究極の牛丼に合う部位はどこか？
Where is the cut that fits the ultimate gyudon?
その味を確かめるため、千肉店からすぐの場所にある川岸牧場グループ店舗「肉料理 樹」にお邪魔しました。
To verify its taste, we visited "Nikuryori Juki," a Kawagishi Livestock Group restaurant right near the Sen-niku shop.
早速なんですけど、どの部位がいいか迷ってて、オススメとか教えていただければなと思っております。
So right away, I'm torn on which cut to get, so I was hoping you could give me some recommendations.
じゃあ本日、あの、3種類ご用意させてもらいました。
Well today, um, we've prepared three types for you.
用意してもらった部位はこちらの3種 この中に牛丼ハンターノエルが納得する部位はあるのでしょうか？
These are the three cuts prepared. Is there a cut among them that satisfies Gyudon Hunter Noel?
まずはサーロインからいただいていきます。
First, we'll try the sirloin.
いい匂いがもうすでに漂ってきてるんですけど
A wonderful aroma is already wafting over.
背中中央部のお肉で脂乗りがよく きめ細かくやわらかい食感の部位
The central back cut, well-marbled with a fine and tender texture.
これってどれぐらい焼けばいいんですかね？
How long should we grill this?
片面をしっかり焼いていただいて、焦げ目がしっかり付くので、そのタイミングで裏返してももらえたらなと。
Grill one side firmly until it gets a good char, then flip it over at that point.
おおー！すげぇ！
Ohh! Amazing!
じゃあいただきます。
Then, let's eat.
美味しい！柔らかくて甘い。
Delicious! Tender and sweet.
続いては、あの芯ロースを。
Next is the "shin-rosu".
肩の芯の部分を抜き取ったお肉で 適度な脂があり柔らかくも噛みごたえのある部位
The core of the shoulder chuck, featuring moderate fat, tenderness, and a satisfying bite.
ほどよく噛みごたえもありでも柔らかくすごく美味しいです。
It has a nice chew yet is tender and extremely delicious.
牛丼って赤身肉が多いんで、いいかもしれないですね。
Gyudon usually has lots of lean meat, so this might be good.
次は赤身の部位で 特選のクリを。
Next is a lean cut, the special "kuri".
クリって聞いたことないんですけどどういった部位になるんですかね？
I've never heard of "kuri." What kind of cut is it?
肩から前脚部にかけての部位で 余計な脂が少なく適度な柔らかさが特徴
The cut from the shoulder to the upper front leg, featuring low excess fat and moderate tenderness.
いただきます。美味しいです。
Let's eat. It's delicious.
先程と違う匂いを感じますよ。
I can smell a different aroma from earlier.
但馬牛の香りはすごく鼻に残るというか、いい香りするんで。
The fragrance of Tajima beef really lingers in the nose, it smells amazing.
やっぱり牛丼って言ったらこういう赤身肉が今イメージに浮かんでるんですけど
When you say gyudon, this kind of lean meat is what comes to mind right now.
いや美味しい、いや悩むなあ。いやこれはもうここまで来たら、いろんなお肉を食べないと結論がつかないかなって思うんで。
Man it's delicious, I'm torn. At this point, I need to try various meats to reach a conclusion.
まず牛丼を見立てて米と、あとねぎ塩タンと
Visualizing gyudon with rice, plus negi-shio tan...
サーロインのユッケがあるって聞いたんですけど？
I heard you have sirloin yukke?
はい、あります。
Yes, we do.
一旦それで考えるととかでもいいですかね？
Could we factor that in as well?
お言葉に甘えて色々選ばさせていただきます。
Taking you up on that, I'll select from a variety.
別に団長が食べないわけではないので、いただきます。
Not that Danchou won't eat it—let's eat!
究極の牛丼作りに関係はあるのか、お味のほどは。
Does it relate to making the ultimate gyudon? How does it taste?
贅沢にいっぱい黄身をつけて こちらいただきたいと思います。
Generously coated in egg yolk, I'd love to try this.
今まで食べたユッケ系で一番美味しいです。
Out of all the yukke I've ever had, this is the most delicious.
団長最近ちょっと鉄の胃袋大魔神と言いつつも油にちょっと負け気味なんですけど
Lately, even though I call myself the 'Iron Stomach Arch-Demon,' I've been a bit sensitive to oily foods.
このユッケだったらあれですね、油っこさも感じずスルッと食べれて。
But with this yukke, you don't feel the greasiness at all, it goes down so smoothly.
これを牛丼にしたら面白そうですよね。
If you made this into a gyudon, it'd be interesting, right?
試食を終え牛丼ハンターノエルが選ぶ究極の部位とは？
Having finished tasting, what is the ultimate cut chosen by Gyudon Hunter Noel?
どれも美味しくてめちゃめちゃ悩むんですよね。
They're all so delicious, I'm agonizing over it.
なんか最後に食べたサーロインのユッケがどうしても忘れられないのと
I just can't forget the sirloin yukke I had last...
あとクリが聞いたこともないし、あとなんかほどよく赤身で
And I've never heard of 'kuri,' plus it has a nice moderate leanness.
この2つを組み合わせて究極牛丼を作ろうかなって思うんですけど、どうですかね？良い案だと思いますか？
I'm thinking of combining these two to make the ultimate gyudon. What do you think? Is it a good idea?
いや、すごくいいと思います。
Yes, I think it's fantastic.
じゃあこの2つの部位をちょっと究極牛丼に使いたいので、あの何卒いただくことはできませんでしょうか？
So since I want to use these two cuts for the ultimate gyudon, would you be so kind as to let us have them?
オッケーです！大丈夫です！ありがとうございます！
Okay! No problem! Thank you so much!
ということで一番の目当てだった神戸牛をゲットしました！
And so, we got our top-target Kobe beef!
続いて牛丼ハンターノエルが向かった先とは？淡路島に来ております！
Next, where did Gyudon Hunter Noel head? We have come to Awaji Island!
淡路といえば玉ねぎ！
Speaking of Awaji, it's onions!
団長は牛丼は甘めでシャキシャキの玉ねぎが好き。
Danchou loves gyudon with sweet and crunchy onions!
ここで最高の玉ねぎ見つけるぞ！いぇーい！
Here I'll find the best onion! Yay!
牛丼に欠かせない食材玉ねぎ。
Onions, an indispensable ingredient for gyudon.
究極の玉ねぎを求めて訪れたのは株式会社善太さんのフルーツ玉ねぎ農園。
In search of the ultimate onion, we visited Zenta Co., Ltd.'s Fruit Onion Farm.
あそこに人がいますね
There's someone over there.
おーい
Yoo-hoo!
作業中に申し訳ないですけど お話聞いてもいいですか？
Sorry to interrupt your work, but could we ask you a few questions?
はーい 行きまーす
Sure, coming!
お仕事中に… いいえ、大丈夫です
In the middle of work... No, it's totally fine.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
ちなみになんですけど 先ほど何されてたんですか？
By the way, what were you doing just now?
今のは玉ねぎを植え付けしておりました
We were planting onions.
ここら辺は全部玉ねぎ畑っちゅうことで 団長が探してたやつです！
This whole area is full of onion fields— exactly what the Leader was looking for!
ありがとうございます
Thank you!
今お手元に持たれてるのは その玉ねぎ？
And what you're holding in your hands right now is...
うちで取れたフルーツ玉ねぎです
These are "fruit onions" harvested right here.
フルーツって めちゃめちゃ甘いっちゅうこと？
"Fruit onions"? Does that mean they're super sweet?
そういうことになりますね フルーツぐらい甘い玉ねぎです
Exactly. They're as sweet as fruit.
レンジでチンした 柔らかくした玉ねぎがあるんで よかったらそれを試食してもらって
We have some microwaved, softened onions, so please feel free to try them.
あーうれしい
Oh, yay!
ありがとうございます じゃあちょっといただきたいと思います
Thank you so much. I'd love to try some.
うん！
Mm!
甘い！
Sweet!
こりゃうまい！
This is so good!
最高糖度11度で 甘さは梨やみかんと同程度
With a maximum sugar content of 11, it's as sweet as pears or mandarins.
この玉ねぎ畑の前からクエスチョンです
Here's a question right from the onion field:
Q. 淡路フルーツ玉ねぎがめちゃくちゃ甘い理由は？
Q. Why are Awaji fruit onions so incredibly sweet?
ヒントはこの絶景！
The hint is this breathtaking scenery!
ということで 早速回答記入タイムでございます
With that, it's time to write down our answers right away!
景色っていうとね やっぱりなんだろうな 育つのに何が必要かなってとこだよね
When you say "scenery"... I wonder what's necessary for them to grow.
何か違うところあるよね 普通の畑と
There has to be something different from normal fields, right?
分かった分かった！
I got it, I got it!
分かった そしたらマリンの団長お前やつ全部ペコラによこして 次！
Okay, then Marine, Commander, hand all your points over to Pekora, next!
何でよ
Why would I do that?!
え、あれじゃない？
Huh, isn't it that?
いや待って マリンもひらめいたわ 前の浮かれっぷりを見てひらめきました
Wait, Marine had a flash of inspiration too! Seeing you all hyped earlier gave it away.
甘い理由か…
The reason why they're sweet...
どうでしょうか
What do you think?
これ自信ある。さっきのいかがねでこれにかければよかった。二人乗せられたわ。めちゃくちゃウキウキだったじゃん
I'm confident in this. I should've bet on this earlier. I dragged two people along with me. You guys were super excited, weren't you?
これだわ、絶対。ほかの違うぺこらだもんね体ね
This is definitely it. The others are different from Pekora's body, right?
そうそうそうそうそう。だよね？あそこに映ってるからね。全てがほら
Exactly, exactly. Right? Because it's reflected right there. Everything, see?
あ、じゃあこれだ。じゃあこれ…だって映ってるやつ描いた。でもこれ漢字簡単だから。でもペコラバカだから書けないんだ
Ah, so it's this. So this... Because I drew what was reflected. But this kanji is easy. Though Pekora is dumb so she can't write it.
でさ、それで悩んでたと。なるほどね
And so, you were struggling with that. I see.
ノエルはこれ答え知ってんの？
Noel, do you know the answer to this?
うん、知ってる！
Yup, I know!
あ、なるほどね
Ah, I see.
で、あのさっきの、でも忘れてたから、ちょっとペコちゃんの今のあの映像に映ってるっていうので思い出した
But I'd forgotten it, so seeing Pekora's answer reflected on screen just now made me remember!
あ、よかったよかった
Ah, good for you.
自分で出したヒントじゃないですか！
That was a hint you gave out yourself!
確かに…
True...
じゃあマリンちゃんはどうですか？どうでしょう
So Marine-chan, how about you? What do you think?
いやもう、うーん、これね…
Well, um, this is...
オッケーです。バッチリですね
Okay! That's spot on.
はい、それでは回答揃いましたので、ではまた団長以外の3人の回答
Alright, everyone's answers are in, so let's reveal the answers from the three members other than the Leader,
一斉に表示していきます
all at once!
さあ！
Here we go!
ほらこれ、揃っちゃうよ
Look at this, they're all lined up!
なんかめちゃめちゃオープンだね
Man, this is super open.
すごいすごい、なるほどなるほど。え、待って、なんて書いてあるのそれ
Wow, wow, I see, I see. Wait, what does that say?
潮風？風？風のこと？
Sea breeze? Wind? Is it about wind?
ばかやろうが、スイカとかに塩かけたら甘くなるだろ！
You idiots, if you put salt on watermelons and stuff, they get sweeter!
てことは、潮風にどんどんどんどんってやったらタマネギも甘くなって育つの？
So that means if sea breezes hit them more and more, onions get sweet and grow?
タマネギってさ、根菜だから下で育ってんじゃないの？
Aren't onions root vegetables, so they grow underground?
え、違うの？
Huh, is that wrong?
あれ？みんな死んじゃったじゃん
Huh? Everyone died!
みんな死んじゃったじゃん
Everyone died!
え、だって上にこうやってさ、なってたっけ？下じゃない？下じゃないね、ぺこら。潮風当たる？ねえねえ、ねえ
Wait, were they growing upwards like this? Isn't it underground? Not underground, right, Pekora? Do sea breezes hit them? Hey, hey, hey!
当たる！
They hit them!
潮風が吸い込んだ土で育つねん、お前は。なるほど、なるほど
They grow in soil that has absorbed the sea breeze, you see. I see, I see.
そういうことよ。ペコラがいたって海か風かみたいなね
That's what I mean. Pekora was like "is it the sea or the wind?" or something.
いや、これ、潮風です。海見えたもん
No, this is "sea breeze." We could see the ocean, after all.
ま、それ言うとマリンも、はい。マリンもですね、こちら「絶景の海水（※上質）を吸っている」ということで
Well, speaking of which, Marine too. Marine's answer is: "absorbing the seawater from the picturesque scenery (※ high quality)."
やっぱ土が、この絶景の海のこのいい水を吸って育っていると、ま考え方は一緒
So the soil absorbs this great water from the scenic ocean and grows—basically the same train of thought.
順調に育ってってことか
So they're growing smoothly, huh?
そう、え？え、海水で育ったら土、あれじゃない？死んじゃうんだよ
Right. Wait, if they grow in seawater, wouldn't the soil... wouldn't they die?
え？違うの？
Huh? Is that wrong?
え、違うの？え、でも水飲んだら…
Huh, wrong? But if they drink water...
それではマリン、どうですか？
Well then, Marine, what about you?
マリン、別とは、ま、賭けるほどの事でもないよね
Marine, as for me... well, it's nothing worth betting points on, right?
でも塩分はね、海水って知ってるのかよ
But you know about the salt content and seawater, right?
まだ、次で、次で。次に賭けます
Let's save it for next time. I'll bet on the next one.
あ、じゃあここでは温存しておくということで
Ah, so you're saving it for now, then.
では、フレア先輩はどうでしょう
Now, how about Flare-senpai?
全然多分、関係ない気がしてきた…気温の変化
I've started to feel like this probably has nothing to do with it... temperature changes.
景色関係ないじゃんそんなの
Scenery has nothing to do with it, seriously!
関係ない
Nothing to do with it!
だって頭アホだもん、ここらないよね
Because our brains are dumb, we can't figure it out.
それではですね、皆さんお待ちかねの、お待たせのバッファロータイムを決めちゃうぞー！
Alright everyone, it's time for the long-awaited Buffalo Time! Let's decide it!
決めちゃうぞということで見ていきましょう。こちら！
Let's check out the results right here!
三宅さんの笑顔♡ / ノエル
[Miyake-san's smile♡ / Noel]
育ててるよな?
Isn't that right?
ねえ!
Yeah!
Right?
いや、でも、聞いてほしい。
Well, but you gotta hear this.
めっちゃ笑顔で、
With a big smile...
なんかしこもやっぱさ、あの、関西だからさ、
And since they're from Kansai,
ゴテゴテの関西弁でノリのいい人で、
with that heavy Kansai dialect and cheerful vibe,
いや「これだったら甘くなるわ」って……
"No wonder they get so sweet!"...
あー、それ自分で考えたやつやろ、絶対!
Hold on, you're just making that up!
いってえ、どこまで上手に書けたからって、まだゴテゴテ書き続けてない。
Just because you can write in Kansai dialect smoothly doesn't mean you can keep making it up!
なるほど。声をかけると甘くなると、
I see. So talking to them makes them sweet.
あ、そうそう。あの、よくね、植物とかね、なんかくさ、やっぱこうきれいな…
Right, right. You know how with plants,
きれいだよ、言うとぱあってなるから。
if you tell them they're pretty, they grow all big and sweet!
甘いって。
That's sweet!
思ったよ。マリも最初に考えたのは、
I thought so too. Marine first thought
この景色をタマネギが見て育ってるって思ったの。
that onions grow watching this scenery.
でもよく考えたら、根菜だから土の中かって思ったの。
But then I thought, wait, onions are root veggies, so are they underground?
でもこいつは、こいつは潮風を受けてるって…
But this one, this one gets the sea breeze!
いってきた!
I figured it out!
どっちなんだよー!
Which one is it?
どうですか、じゃあ団長これ自信のほうは…
So, Danchou, how about your confidence?
いや、あ、あるんですけど、
Well, I do have some, but...
まあ、今じゃない。
Well, not right now.
今じゃ、あ、じゃあ今だいにん使うところではない。
Right now? Ah, so right now is not the time to use it?
そうですね。
Right, exactly.
なるほど、わかりました。
I see, understood.
それでは、この中に正解者はいるのでしょうか?
Then, is there anyone here with the correct answer?
正解発表していきましょう!
Let's announce the correct answer!
こちらです!
Here we go!
気温の変化だったら…
Wait, if it's temperature changes...
ほら、見て、出てるぞ!
Wait, look! They're growing!
え、嘘でしょ?
No way!
ほら、中に出てるよ。嘘でしょ?
Look, they're coming out! Is that real?
由来出る?
Let's see...
さあ、こちら、
And the answer is:
ミネラルが土壌に含有されているためでございます!
Because the soil is rich in minerals!
潮風でやろう、これ。
That's what sea breeze means?
潮風ってどういうこと?この、ぺこらちゃん。
What does sea breeze have to do with it, Pekora-chan?
そういうわけでございます。
So that's how it is.
ということで、これは、
So, this means...
土壌にミネラルが含まれているからということで…
the soil contains minerals!
淡路島の土壌にはですね、
Awaji Island's soil...
潮風、
sea breeze...
などによって海のミネラルが…
brings in sea minerals,
海のミネラルがしみ込んでいるんです。
which soak right into the soil!
なのでミネラルが豊富な土壌は、水はけがよく、
So, soil rich in minerals has great drainage,
余分な水分が玉ねぎに吸収されず、
preventing excess water from being absorbed by the onions,
甘くなるということで…
making them sweet...
厳しく育って甘くなるということなんですの!
meaning they grow tough and sweet!
ぺこら先輩文句なしの大正解です!
Pekora-senpai got it completely right!
玉ねぎが風を浴びてると言って…
She said onions drink the sea breeze!
あの、ミネラルがっていうところはまあ、ちょっと、省略しているということだから、まあ、惜しい。
Well, she missed that the minerals soak in,
いや、惜しく。
Yeah, so close!
マリーンもちょっと惜しかったけど、
Marine's was a bit off too,
話を聞くと海水で育ったみたいな感じの、
but hearing her story about growing in seawater,
ちょっと違う全然違うこと言ってたので、
she said something totally different,
今回は残念ながら…
so unfortunately...
フレアがマリーン使ったから。
Flare used Marine's answer.
総合的に私のが正解ってことで…
So comprehensively, mine was correct...
何言ってんだお前は!
What are you talking about?
関係ないよ、お前は!
You have nothing to do with this, Flare!
はい。
Right.
ということで、
So with that,
正解したぺこら先輩がプラス1ポイントとなりまして、
Pekora-senpai gets +1 point,
1ポイント。
bringing her to 1 point!
あとの3人、団長も含め3人は残念ながらまだ0ポイントでございますが、
The other three, including Danchou, are still at 0 points.
でもまだ可能性ありますからね。
Well, there are still chances!
そうですね、まだ先頭してますね。
That's true, we're just getting started.
え、待って、でも次正解しても4ptじゃね?
Wait, if I get the next one right, is it 4 points?
え、待って、4ポイント。
Wait, 4 points?
あれ、ちょっと、結構厳しいか?
Wait, is this getting a bit tough?
あれ、ぺこら、2ポイント。
Wait, Pekora has 2 points.
足りないよ?
Not enough?
なんかちょっと、牛丼食べられるか怪しくなってきましたね。
It's starting to look doubtful whether we can even eat gyudon...
まあまあ、でも、諦めだめですからね、皆さん。
Well, you shouldn't give up just yet, everyone.
まだ色んな可能性がございますからね。
There are still various possibilities!
大丈夫でございます。
Everything will be fine.
それでは、VTRの続き、
Now then, let's continue with the VTR!
どうぞー!
Here we go!
美味しかったです、ありがとうございます。
It was delicious, thank you very much.
今ちょっと植え付けの途中で、
Right now, we're in the middle of planting,
玉ねぎの実物がないので、
so we don't have actual onions right now.
ちょっと倉庫の方に保管してるやつを、よかったら、行きたいです!
If you'd like, we can go check out the ones stored in the warehouse—
大量にあるんですよね?はい、あります。
They have a huge amount, right? Yes, we do!
はい、行きます!
Let's go!
農園から30分ほど離れた、
A 30-minute drive from the farm,
本社にある倉庫内を特別に見せていただくことに。
we get a special tour inside the headquarters warehouse!
こちらが倉庫ですかね?
This is the warehouse?
あ、そうですね。
Yes, it is.
この中に玉ねぎがいっぱい入ってます。
There are lots of onions inside.
ここですか。なるほど。
In here? I see.
じゃあ、一度開けてみましょうか。
Then let's open it up and take a look.
はい、お願いします。
Yes, please.
そうやって、あ。
Let's see...
ええー!
Whoa!
これ全部玉ねぎですか?
Are these all onions?
すごい冷気が。
It's so cold in here!
あと、なんかすごい寒いんですけど、何度?
It's freezing! What temperature is it?
今で2°Cくらい。
It's around 2°C right now.
1度2度ぐらいです。
About 1 to 2°C.
この2°Cで保管してるのは何か理由が?
Is there a reason they're kept at 2°C?
玉ねぎの芽が出ないように、
To keep the onions from sprouting
収穫した時の状態を保つために。
and to maintain the condition they were in when harvested.
先ほど食べさせていただいて、
Earlier, I got to taste one,
思い描いてる牛丼にすごいイメージが合うなって思ったんですけど、
and I thought it fit the gyudon I'm imagining so well.
どうですか、なんか特徴とかも合いそうですかね?
do you think its characteristics match up too?
肉厚でジューシーで、
Thick, juicy,
あの、非常に甘くて柔らかいので、
and very sweet and tender,
合うと思います。
so I think it'll be a great match.
太鼓判を押してもらって、
With your seal of approval,
なんかさらに、ちょっと牛丼のイメージが沸きました。
I have an even clearer image of the gyudon now.
ありがとうございます!
Thank you very much!
善太さんの淡路フルーツ玉ねぎを、ぜひ、
Please let us use Zenta's Awaji fruit onions
究極の牛丼に使わせてください!
for our ultimate gyudon!
究極牛丼玉ねぎゲット!
Ultimate Gyudon Onion Get!
はい。
Right,
ということでですね、ロケの様子のアイルを見ていただきましたが、
so we just watched the location VTR.
皆さんいかがでしたでしょうか?
how was it, everyone?
食べたい!
I want to eat it!
すごい全部食べたことないよ、だって。
I've never eaten all of these before!
ステーキの部位も、
Even the steak cuts,
この玉ねぎも初めてのフルーツ玉ねぎ、
and these onions—my first time seeing fruit onions!
全部食べたことない!経験しないとこれは、
I've never eaten any of it! You really have to experience it.
やっぱりみんな食べたいよね?
Everyone wants to eat it, right?
食べたい!
We do!
We want to eat it!
まあ、食べたいということで、
Well, since we want to eat it,
なんと後半はですね、
for the second half,
その集めた食材たちを使って、
we'll use the ingredients we collected
究極の牛丼を調理していく。
to cook the ultimate gyudon!
究極の牛丼を調理していくという様子を見てもらおうと思っているんですが…
I'm thinking of having you watch me cook the ultimate gyudon, but...
が…ま、その前にライブパートでーす。ライブパート？
but... well, before that, it's the live part! Live part?
ほめのび 作詞・作曲:渡辺翔
[Song: Homenobi / Lyrics & Music: Sho Watanabe]
練習中 練習中
Practicing, practicing,
しれっとこそっと準備進行
sneakingly making preparations,
心中緊張で焦る
feeling nervous and anxious inside.
言うけど強々ありでしょ?
Saying that, being strong is fine, right?
元気こぼるから待っちょって
Energy is spilling out, so wait up!
そうやって成長するのです
That's how we grow and develop.
いいかな?
Is that okay?
ゆるポンでOK?
Is a loose pon OK?
いちにのさんで
One, two, three,
テンパっちゃってOK?
freaking out is OK?
始めっちゃおう
Let's get started!
ほめてほしいな ほめてほしいな
I want you to praise me, praise me!
ほめてくれたら二度寝なしで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll do my best without going back to sleep!
見ててほしいな 見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me, watch me!
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I'm the type who grows when praised to high heaven!
ours 作詞・作曲:古川本舗
[Song: ours / Lyrics & Music: Furukawa Honpo]
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
Today isn't a final goodbye,
手を取ってくれたなら
if you take my hand.
秘密も眠りに就くような夜に
On a night when even secrets fall asleep,
君を連れてくよ
I'll take you along.
それは例えば遠く離れていたって
Even if we were far apart, for instance,
手を繋いでいられるような
like being able to hold hands,
奇跡のような話をしよう
let's talk about something like a miracle.
窓を開けといて
Keep the window open.
今日までを思い出して
Remembering up until today,
一つ一つ並べたら
when I line them up one by one,
明日の雨が気になりだして
I start worrying about tomorrow's rain
どうも眠れないみたいだ
and somehow I can't seem to sleep.
変わりたくないことや変わらなきゃいけないことも
Things I don't want to change, and things I must change—
少し忘れたまま窓の外を眺めていたんだ
forgetting them a little, I was gazing out the window.
雨が降り出すその前に
Before the rain starts to fall,
君のところまで行けるような気がして
I feel like I can make it all the way to where you are.
目を閉じてこのまま遠くへと行こう
Closing my eyes, let's go far away just like this,
手をとってくれるかな
will you take my hand?
秘密も眠りに就くような夜を
A night where even secrets fall asleep,
君と泳いでいくよ
I will swim through it with you.
街の明りが消える度に笑って
Smiling every time the city lights go out,
路地裏で抱き合おう
let's embrace in the back alley.
馬鹿みたいな話をしよう
Let's talk about silly things,
窓を開けといて聞こえる?
keep the window open, can you hear it?
ラヴミーテンダー 作詞・作曲:TOKOTOKO
[Song: Love Me Tender / Lyrics & Music: TOKOTOKO]
位置について よーいどんで
On your mark, get set, and go!
周回遅れで
A lap behind,
明日は二周遅れ?
tomorrow is two laps behind?
あのね 理由もなく不安になる日は
You know, days when I feel uneasy for no reason
心が疲れてる証拠
are proof that my heart is tired.
でもね 笑う角には福も見に来てかもって
But hey, they say fortune visits smiling faces,
Oh Baby What a Beautiful Day!
Oh Baby What a Beautiful Day
うろ覚えの歌詞も 曖昧なメロディも
Even half-remembered lyrics and vague melodies
君と歌えば ほら名曲になる
become masterpieces when I sing them with you!
友達以上が 未満かより
More than friends, less than lovers—
名前のない特別な距離
a special distance with no name.
昨日の失敗も 明日の憂鬱も
Yesterday's failures and tomorrow's blues,
君と話せば 笑い話になる
turn into funny stories when I talk with you.
どこにいても 何をしてても 声は飛んでく 君方向へ
No matter where I am or what I do, my voice flies toward you.
どんより雨降りも しょんぼり泣き虫も
Gloomy rainy days and gloomy crybabies—
君にかかれば ほら キラキラ光る
when it involves you, look, they shine sparkling bright!
嬉しい楽しいが もっと増えてく
Joy and fun just keep multiplying,
無邪気な子供のように 抱きしめて
so hold me tight like an innocent child.
君に逢いたい
I want to see you.
ということで後半戦になります！イェーイ！
That means we're entering the second half! Yay!
これ挽回できるんですかー？
Can we make a comeback from thisー?
確かに出発ゼロポイントなんですけど
True, we're at zero points,
ゼロポイントの方も多いですし
and there are a lot of zero-point people too,
ちょっと現状ちょっと狙らすと1問になりますんで！
so for the current situation, we're down to just one final question!
えーーー！？
Eeeeehー!?
あたってもね...ペコら1問しかあたってないけど、あたっても無理だよね...
Even if I get it right... Pekora only got one right, so even if she gets it right, it's impossible...
そうですね無理ですねもうだって
That's right, it's impossible, because...
えっ？どうすんだっけ？もうだって、ほら先輩はね
Huh? What were we doing? Because, look, Senpai...
でも団長はしごかけちゃおうかな...
But maybe I'll put pressure on the Leader...
あっ、はしごかけちゃ...
Ah, put pressure...
まあまあちょっとそんなね、大丈夫ですよ！きっと
Well, well, a little bit like that, it'll be fine! Surely.
まあまあまあ、ま、とりあえず、あのVTRをどうぞ！
Well, well, well, well, anyway, please roll the VTR!
数日後
A few days later
さてさて、都内に戻ってきました！
Now then, we're back in Tokyo!
その後続々と必要な食材を全て集めたので、早速作っていきたいところなのですが...
After that, we gathered all the necessary ingredients one after another, so we're ready to start making it, but...
まあ、最高の食材があっても、この食材を使える最高の料理人がいないと、究極の牛丼にはならないよね。
Well, even if you have the best ingredients, without the best chef who knows how to use them, it won't become the ultimate beef bowl.
ということで、神戸牛と言ったらこの方をお呼びしました！どうぞ！
And so, when it comes to Kobe beef, we invited this person! Here they are!
こんにちは
Hello.
今回料理を担当するのは...
Handling the cooking this time is...
神戸牛ダイア雷門西店 料理長 佐々木康二さん
Koji Sasaki, Head Chef of Kobe Beef Daia Kaminarimon-Nishi.
本日は佐々木料理長監修のもと、究極の牛丼を作っていきたいと思います。
Today, under the supervision of Head Chef Sasaki, we're going to make the ultimate beef bowl.
というわけで、早速作っていきたいと思います。
So without further ado, let's start making it.
まずは淡路フルーツ玉ねぎ1個分を炒める
First, stir-fry one Awaji fruit onion.
玉ねぎは低温でゆっくり火を通すことにより甘みがすごく出るので美味しくなります
Cooking onions slowly at a low temperature brings out immense sweetness and makes them delicious.
水400ml・砂糖 大さじ5・しょうゆ 大さじ6・顆粒和風だし 小さじ4・みりん 大さじ2・料理酒 大さじ2
400ml water, 5 tbsp sugar, 6 tbsp soy sauce, 4 tsp dashi granules, 2 tbsp mirin, 2 tbsp cooking sake.
ひとふかしするまでゆっくり火を入れていきます
Simmer slowly until it comes to a light boil.
それではお肉を入れていきます
Now we'll add the meat.
神戸牛（部位:クリ）400gをほぐしながら入れる
Add 400g of Kobe beef (cut: shoulder clod), breaking it apart as you put it in.
お肉に火が通り出したらアクが出てくるので丁寧に取り除いてください
Once the meat starts cooking, scum will appear, so please carefully skim it off.
このまま約10分ほど炊いていきます
Simmer it just like this for about 10 minutes.
煮込んでいる間に サーロインユッケ作りへ
While simmering, making sirloin yukke
フライパンに牛脂を塗って神戸牛（サーロイン）300gを乗せる
Grease the pan with beef tallow and place 300g of Kobe beef (sirloin) in it.
塩・コショウ 少々
A pinch of salt and pepper.
お肉の旨味が逃げないように全体をよく焼いていきます
Sear the whole piece well so the meat's delicious juices don't escape.
薄く切る
Cut into thin slices.
ユッケダレ（調味料）と混ぜる
Mix with the yukke sauce (seasoning).
炙りサーロインユッケ完成
Aburi sirloin yukke complete!
料理長！高級なお肉がないときはどうすれば手軽に美味しい牛肉になるんでしょうか？
Head Chef! When you don't have high-end meat, how can you easily make delicious beef?
家庭でもよく食べる安いお肉でも美味しい牛肉に出来る簡単な方法ってあったりしませんか？
Isn't there some simple method to turn even cheap meat we usually eat at home into delicious beef?
家庭でも美味しい柔らかいお肉を作るひと工夫としてブライイン液を使うといいかもしれません
As a trick to make delicious, tender meat even at home, using a brine solution might be good.
なに〜！？ブライイン液？
Whatー?! A brine solution?
ということで最後のクエスチョンです！ブライイン液は水ととある調味料2つを組み合わせた液となります
And now for the final question! A brine solution is a liquid combining water and two specific seasonings.
一体何の組み合わせでしょうか？
Exactly what combination is it?
名をすべて当ててください！
Guess all of their names!
なんと今回は一発逆転
This is a chance for a huge comeback,
超高得点ゲットのチャンスだよ！
getting a massive amount of points!
みんな頑張ってね！動き動き！
Everyone do your best! Move, move!
こんなことないでしょなんだこれ。ヒント、ヒント！
There's no way, what is this? A hint, a hint!
逆転ボーナスチャンスということで
As a comeback bonus chance,
皆様、机の下をご覧ください！
everyone, please look under your desks!
なになに？なんだこれ！？なんじゃこりゃ！はい、皆さん、YAGOOがいましーた！
What's this? What is this?! What in the world! Yes everyone, YAGOO is here!
こちらのYAGOOをBETすることができまして、BETするとなんと…
You can bet this YAGOO, and if you bet...
なんと何倍！？10倍です！
What, how many times?! 10 times!
今までのなんだったんだ！そうだ、最初から動きで…
What was all that until now! That's right, from the start we wanted movement...
1ポイントに10倍だから、それだけでペコラ先輩でさえも勝てるということで
1 point becomes 10 times, so just with that, even Pekora-senpai can win!
おー！食べれるぺこ！でもブライン液がわかんない…ブライン液がわかんないからということで皆様回答の記入をお願いいたします！
Oh! I can eat, peko! But I don't know what brine is... Since I don't know brine, everyone, please write down your answers!
問題！問題！ヒント欲しい、ヒント欲しい！
Question! Question! I want a hint, I want a hint!
まあ、料理する人は知ってるかもしれないんですけどね
Well, people who cook might know this,
水100mlに対して…んー、5g？
for 100ml of water... um, 5g?
5g？5g？
5g? 5g?
調味料ってこと？グラムだよ！
A seasoning? It's in grams!
皆さんの家に絶対ある。ある！全員ある、多分。自炊をするならば、幾％ありますよ。グラム？
It's definitely in everyone's house. Yes! Everyone has it, probably. If you cook for yourself, it's a certain percentage. Grams?
見たことないってことはない。だって、液体だったらさっきみたいに100mlっていうけど、液体じゃない。グラム系のものね。絶対ある本当！
It's not like you've never seen it. Because if it's liquid, like earlier, we'd say 100ml, but it's not liquid. It's measured in grams. It's definitely there, really!
絶対にあるよ。カナタ絶対みんなあるの、絶対みんなあるよ。
It's definitely there. Kanata, everyone definitely has it, everyone definitely has it.
こいつちょっと書き始めて顔をこうして
This guy started writing and put his face like this...
これ違うぞ。これペコラのどう？
This is wrong. What about Pekora's?
これさ、みんなの家にもあるよね？もっともっともっとメジャーなやつ。みんなの家にある？そう。
Everyone has this in their house, right? Something much, much more major. Does everyone have it in their house? Yes.
え、違う！私見てて！
Eh, no! Look at me!
これは何？
What is this?
おいフレア、10倍じゃねえぞ！まだ食べれねえぞ！
Hey Flare, it's not 10 times! We still can't eat!
フレア頑張れ生きるぞ！おそい！おそい！
Flare do your best, stay alive! Slow! Slow!
そこまで来たら答えは1つじゃないですか。
Once you've come this far, isn't the answer obvious?
そろそろ時間か～？
Is it almost time~?
うわー、ちょっと待って！
Whoa, wait a second!
あれ、団長…？
Huh, Danchou...?
え？ちょ…？
Eh? Wha...?
あいのかえるくえねぽたんあるか、これは。あれ、さっきの。
Is there an Aino Kaeru Kuenepotan? Huh, from earlier.
はい！ということで皆様ね、回答が出揃ってきましたということで、ではまた、団長以外の3人の回答を一斉に表示していきましょう！
Yes! So everyone, your answers are all in, so let's display the answers of the other three members all at once!
だーん！
Ta-da!
えーっと、ペコラ先輩と周りのやつ邪魔だな！
Um, Pekora-senpai and the surrounding stuff are in the way!
YAGOOの顔で、あ、はい、塩、砂糖、そして
With YAGOO's face, ah yes, salt, sugar, and
え、フレア先輩が塩、胡椒…。あ、それは間違えるわ！
Eh, Flare-senpai put salt, pepper... Ah, of course you'd get that wrong!
まあね、わかんない、絶対わかんないですよ、わかんないですけれどもっと
Well yeah, you don't know, you definitely don't know, but more...
これでフレアあってたらどうする？カナダとバナでさ、これね。
What if Flare is right? Kanata and Bana... wait.
どうする？どんどん、どんどんと可能性はあるけど、じゃあまりーんどうしますか？BETしますかしますよ当たり前っしょ！
What should we do? There's more and more possibilities, but Marine, what will you do? Will you bet? Of course we will!
団員さーん！すみません、団員さん！いらっしゃい！
Danyiin-saan! Excuse me, Danyiin-saan! Come on out!
全BETでいきますか！いらっしゃい！はいはい、来ました！
Can we go with all-in BET? Come on out! Yes yes, here they come!
あ、じゃあ団員さんとYAGOO全BET！はい、全BETでいきます！
Ah, then Danyiin-saan and YAGOO all-in BET! Yes, all-in BET!
これであたってたら40ポイントもらえますからね！
If this is correct, we get 40 points!
やばい、YAGOOが起きてる！YAGOO！
Oh no, YAGOO is awake! YAGOO!
YAGOO落ちてた？なんか、ありが、なんか、ケツだな…。ケツだな、並べてと。なるほどね。
YAGOO fell? It looks like, kind of, a butt... A butt, lined up. I see.
じゃあ、えっとフレア先輩、掛けないと終わるので掛けます。
Well, um, Flare-senpai, if you don't bet it ends, so you bet.
あの団員さんも呼んでてください。団員さんおいで！
Please call Danyiin-saan too. Danyiin-saan, come here!
来たわ！もし当たってるかもしれないからね！
They're here! Because we might actually get it right!
フレア先輩も全BETということで
Flare-senpai is also all-in BET,
じゃあ、ペコラ先輩！ペコラはYAGOO人形かけまーす！
so then, Pekora-senpai! Pekora is betting the YAGOO doll!
おお、来ました！みんなもBETして行きますね、YAGOOが揺れております！
Oh, here it comes! Everyone is betting too, YAGOO is shaking!
それではですね、えーっと、じゃあ、団長の答え見ていきましょうか！こちらです！はい！
Well then, um, let's look at Danchou's answer! Here it is! Yes!
これ自信がありますよ。
I'm confident about this.
やっぱり！
Definitely!
甘いのとしょっぱいので無限ループということで
It's sweet and salty, an infinite loop!
はい、こちら！
Yes, please.
柔らかくの。
Softly...
おねげぇしまーす！
Please!
いいよ、採用していくと。
So we'll take that.
ということで、まぁ最終問題ですのでね。
Since this is the final question, right?
では、この中に正解者いるのでしょうか？
Let's see if the correct answer is in here!
正解はこちら！
The correct answer is this!
水100mlに対して、砂糖5g・塩5gでございまーす！
Water 100ml to 5g of sugar and 5g of salt!
大丈夫、みんなで1ポイントずつ分けてあげるから。
Don't worry, everyone gets 1 point each, so...
そうなんだ、塩と砂糖でございましたー！
That's right, it's salt and sugar!
塩と砂糖！
Salt and sugar!
確かにこれなら全部の家庭にあるね。
That's right, these are in every household.
絶対にね。
Definitely.
そうなんですよ。
Yeah, they are.
ということでね、えー、まぁこちらのね、結果についてはVTR後にちょっと振り返っていきたいと思います！
So, we'll look back at the results after the VTR!
おもいますので、それでは、
So...
VTRの続き、スタート！
VTR continuation, start!
究極牛丼の完成に向けて残りは盛り付けのみ、しかしその前に…
Approaching the ultimate gyudon, leaving only the plating... But before that...
料理今日、団長は
Cooking today, Danchou...
玉ねぎのシャキシャキ感もめちゃ好きなんですよねー。
I really love the crisp texture of onions, you know!
ノエルさんが持ってきたフンドーキンの醤油を使って、ひと工夫していきましょう。
Using the Fundokin soy sauce Noel brought, let's add a special touch!
この醤油は…
This soy sauce is...
団長のMy Favorite醤油！
Danchou's My Favorite soy sauce!
ねえ。
Yeah.
玉ねぎとフンドーキン醤油を和える。
Mix the onions with Fundokin soy sauce.
ちょっと甘いんですよ、普通の醤油より。
It's a bit sweeter than regular soy sauce.
美味しそう！
Looks delicious!
それでは盛り付けていきます、大盛りでおねがいします。
Now, we'll start plating. Generously, please.
わかりました。
Got it.
wwwwww
淡路玉ねぎフンドーキン醤油和えを乗せていきます。
Add the Awaji onion mixed with Fundokin soy sauce.
神戸牛の炙り肉を置いていきます。
Place the seared Kobe beef on top.
美味しそう！
Looks delicious!
うわ、すごっ！
Wow, awesome!
すごい！
Amazing!
最後に薬味のネギを散らしていきまーす。
Finally, sprinkle some chopped green onions on top.
完成でございます。
And it's done!
いただきまーす！
Let's eat!
究極の牛丼完成！
The ultimate gyudon is complete!
できました！うわ、究極！
We did it! Ultimate!
なんと美しいんでしょうか！
How exquisite is this?!
スタジオのみんなはどれだけ正解できたかな？
I wonder how many points everyone in the studio got?
それでは、お待たせの試食タイムー！
And now, the long-awaited tasting time!
というわけでですね、正解は…
So, the correct answer is...
団長とマリン先輩！で不正解は…
Danchou and Marine-senpai got it right, and the incorrect answer is...
フレア先輩！
Furare-senpai!
冷静に考えたらウチこしょうねぇや！
If I'd thought about it calmly, it wouldn't be pepper!
そうでした。はい、じゃあ皆さんのですね、
That's right. So, everyone's...
あの、ポイントの方もちょっと発表していきましょうか。
points as well, let's announce them!
えっと、なんとですね、フレア先輩はゼロポイントになります！
And what is that? Surprisingly, Flare-senpai has 0 points!
そして、ぺこら先輩11ポイント！
And Pekora-senpai has 11 points!
そしてノエル団長が20ポイント！
And Noel-danchou has 20 points!
そしてなんとマリンが40ポイント！
And Marine has 40 points!
優勝！
Winner!
我慢してよかった！
I held back, and I'm glad I did.
最後まで温存してよかったというところで、
I'm glad I kept my composure until the end.
そういうわけですね、残念ながらフレア先輩だけが…
So, unfortunately, Flare-senpai alone...
ゼロポイント！ここで食べられないと！かわいそう！
No points! That means she can't eat it here. How heartless!
こんなことってあっていいんですか、団長？
Is it okay to do things like this, Danchou?
いや、悲しいよ…。
Well, it's sad.
いや、いいよ、しょうがねぇ…。
Well, it can't be helped...
いや、待って！
Wait!
この…ポキ…？どういうこと？
This... poki? What?
ということで、団長どっち！10ポイントあげる！
So, Danchou, give 10 points to Flare!
という、団長の20ポイント中の10ポイントで、はい。
So Danchou's 20 points becomes 10 points!
そんなことがいいんですか？
Is that even okay?
これで、全員もしかして食べられるということになり…。
Does that mean everyone might be able to eat now?
いいですか？
Is that okay?
いいみたい！やったー！
It looks like it! Yay!
いや、あったけぇ世界だー！
Man, what a heartwarming world!
じゃあ皆でね、食べていきましょうか！
So, shall we all eat together?
食べましょー！
Let's eat!
究極牛丼！
Ultimate gyudon!
すごい！
Awesome!
食べたい！
Let's eat!
すごい、すごい、すごい！
So amazing, amazing, amazing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
どうぞ！
Enjoy!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you!
めちゃいい匂い！
It smells so good!
いただきます、いただきます！
Can we eat? Let's eat!
食べてもいいんですか、みんなで。
Can we all eat together?
いただきまーす！
Let's dig in!
うぇーい！
Awesome!
なんていい番組なんだ…。
What a great program...
神様じゃん。
It's a gift from the gods.
団長ありがとう。
Thank you, Danchou.
皆で食べたら究極よ。
It's ultimate when everyone eats together.
食べます！
Let's eat!
うま！めちゃめちゃ美味しい！
It's so good!
初めて食べたみたいな…。
Eating gyudon for the first time...
んふふ、んふふ。
Mmh! Mmh!
えっ、甘！
Huh, sweet!
あまっ！たまねぎ！
So sweet, the onions!
究極かもしれない。今まで食べた中で一番美味しい。
This might be the ultimate. It's the best I've ever had!
美味しいの？
Delicious?
うまっ！めっちゃ美味い！一番美味しいの。
It's so good, it's the best!
玉ねぎがこんなに美味しいなんてことがあるんですか？お肉もうま！
Can onions really be this delicious? And the meat is so good!
めちゃ美味い！これ毎日食べたい！
So good! I want to eat this every day!
ねぇ、これ美味しい！
Right? It's so good!
ぺこらちゃん、毎日牛丼が食べたい？
Pekora-chan, do you want to eat gyudon every day?
なるほど！
I see!
ちょっといいですか、皆さんがちょっと食べている間に、ちょっと失敬失敬…。
While everyone is eating, I'll sneak out...
ということで、まぁね、団長ちょっと重大告知ありまーす！
So, Danchou has a major announcement!
なに？
What is it?
団長はホロライブ入ってからずっと牛丼が好きって言って-
Ever since I joined Hololive, I've always said I loved gyudon,
たんですけど、なんと！
but guess what!
この度…牛丼の曲を作りました！
This time... I've created a gyudon song!
やってやったぜ！って話しこんじゃいもん。
I actually did it! I got so caught up talking about it.
ということでね、自分で自発的に曲を作ったので、あの聞いてもらってもいいですか？
So, since I made this song on my own initiative, would you mind listening to it?
食べながらでも全然いいんで。
It's totally fine to eat while listening!
それでは、聞いてください！
So without further ado, please listen!
ぎゅーどんかーにばる！
Gyudon Carnival!
ぎゅっ！どん！ぎゅーどん！どん！
Gyu! Don! Gyudon! Don!
ぎゅっ！どん！ぎゅっとしてドーン！！
Gyu! Don! Squeeze and boom!
ぎゅーどんかーにばる！
Gyudon Carnival!
大好き♥ぎゅっとしてドーン！！
I love you so much♥ Squeeze and boom!
ぽん酢かけてサッパリとハピハピ！
Pour ponzu sauce for a fresh, happy-happy vibe!
濃厚かにとくもり ワイン！
Rich crab seafood topping with wine!
チーズや温泉トッピングはお好み！
Cheese or soft-boiled egg toppings are up to you!
どれも最高 笑顔でキメ太郎
All are top-tier, decided with a smile!
はぁ～い、腹ペコのバブちゃんたち こっちでちよ～
Halloo, all my hungry little babies, come right over here~
食べる前に、お姉さんと運動しちゃうね～
Before we eat, let's do a little workout with big sis~
あーんど、Let's Go!! Hey, Come On!! Everybody Stand up!! Are You Hungry!? O-YEAH!
And... Let's Go!! Hey, Come On!! Everybody Stand up!! Are You Hungry!? O-YEAH!
ギュンギュンギュン牛 からの「いただきまーす！」
Gyu-gyu-gyu beef! And then, "Itadakimasu!"
さあさ牛丼だ 牛丼だ 一緒に食べよう
Come on, it's gyudon, it's gyudon, let's eat together!
キミと仲良く カーニバル トロトロチュウオー！
Carnival in harmony with you, meltingly smooth!
ゴロリお肉 お肉 つまんじゃダメ 全部食べたらほめちゃう
Chunky meat—don't pinch it! Eat it all up and I'll praise you!
なでなでよしよしキュッキュッキュッ もう最高！あびゃぴゃ！
Petting and praising, kyu-kyu-kyu, it's the best! Abyapya!
せーのっ！ぎゅーどん、どーん！
Ready, set! Gyudon, boom!
えっ！？牛丼が嫌い！？
Huh!? You hate gyudon!?
もう、なんでそういうこと言うの！ そんな悪い子は食べちゃうぞ♥
Jeez, why would you say that! Such a bad kid is getting eaten♥
あびゃーあびゃぴゃあびゃぴゃ...（あびゃぴゃ連打）
Abya-abyapya-abyapya... (Rapid abya-abya)
すっきー！すきすき大チュッキー！
Love you! Super-duper big chukky!
ラブユー ラブラブ洗脳中～
Love you, love-love brainwashing~
むっちー！むちむち責めちゃダメ
Muchi! Don't tease me too much, chunky style!
よくできました！ほっぺにちゅ～！
Well done! A kiss on the cheek!
だくだくねぎだくえいっ ところが全然足りません
Daku-daku, negidaku! But it's still not nearly enough!
だくだくつゆだくわぁい それでも全然足りません
Daku-daku, tsuyudaku! Even so, it's nowhere near enough!
だくだくにくたくあん まだまだ全然足りないの
Daku-daku, nikutaku! Still, it's nowhere near enough!
だくだくどくどくきゅんっ ドキがムネムネ止まらな～い
Daku-daku, doku-doku, kyun! My heartbeat won't stop thumping~
牛丼を食べる時は、お口でふーふーして...って、あっ！いきなりがついちゃって、かわいい～♥
When eating gyudon, you blow on it like... wait, ah! You dug right in, how cute~♥
優しく...丁寧に、だぞ？あははっ...良い子良い子。
Gently... and carefully, okay? Ahaha... Good boy, good boy.
お腹、いっぱいになっちゃったね。一緒に、寝ちゃう？おやすみなさ～い
Your tummy's all full now. Want to sleep together? Goodnight~
もしもキミが シュンとしちゃっても
Even if you're feeling down,
ぎゅってぎゅってぎゅって 抱きしめてあげる
I'll hold you tight, tight, tight!
ほら、おいで～～～～！！！
Hey, come here~~~~!!!
さあさ牛丼だ 牛丼だ 一緒に食べよう
Come on, it's gyudon, it's gyudon, let's eat together!
キミと何処でも カーニバル トロトロチュウオー！
Carnival anywhere with you, meltingly smooth!
ゴロリお肉 お肉 つまんじゃダメ 全部食べたらほめちゃう
Chunky meat—don't pinch it! Eat it all up and I'll praise you!
なでなでよしよしキュッキュッキュッ もう最高！あびゃぴゃ！
Petting and praising, kyu-kyu-kyu, it's the best! Abyapya!
せーのっ！ぎゅーどん、どーん！
Ready, set! Gyudon, boom!
大好き♥ぎゅっとしてドーン！！白銀ノエルの牛丼どーーーん！！！ぎゅーーーーっ！
I love you♥ Squeeze and boom!! Shirogane Noel's Gyudon Boooom!!!
いかがでしたでしょうか？新ギャップで、可愛いー！
How was that? Kawaii and energetic!
え、これには意味があるんだって、ノエルやっちゃって。
Wait, there's a reason for this! Noel, do it.
あ、そうですね。じゃあちょっと、あの宣伝あーだこうだ。
Ah, I see. Well then, some advertising...
あ、そうですね、じゃあちょっと、あの宣伝…あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, is that so? Well then, about advertising... Ah, thank you!
ではでは、ちょっとさらにね、告知が続きますということで、
Well then, further announcements will continue,
ま、皆さんもくつろぎながら見てくれると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you all relax while watching.
ということで、今年もあります、こちらどーん！
With that said, it's happening this year too. Here it is, ta-da!
白銀ノエル生誕記念グッズー！
Shirogane Noel's Birthday Commemoration Goods!
お、牛も、牛もおぎゃっとるぞ。
Oh, the cow is mooing too.
そうでしょ、牛は、大自然でございます。では、詳細見ていきましょう。
That's right, cows are in the great outdoors. Now let's check the details.
え、最初は、こちら！ということで、あの、先ほどのイラストを使った、あの、ナルドック先生描き下ろしポストカードフレームになります！
First is this! Using the illustration from earlier, it's a postcard frame drawn by Nardack-sensei!
あ、いいでしょう。
Ah, isn't it nice?
やっぱね、結構さ、我々いろいろね、やっぱサイン入りのポストカードとかね、結構書きますんで、そういうのなんか入れ込めるいいなと思って。
Since we often write signed postcards and things like that, I thought it'd be nice to display them.
だってこういうの、なんか作ったことなかったなということで、ちょっと作ってみました。
I've never made anything like this before, so I tried making one.
こちら…こちらじゃなくて、もうちょいさい…
Here... Not this, a bit more...
半分…あ、でもいいの？半分でいいの？あ、そうかも。いい、いいけどね、なんかフリーダムだなということで、はい、じゃあ次行きましょう、次！
Half... Ah, but is that fine? Half is fine? Well, it's fine, but it's pretty free-spirited. Well then, let's move on to the next!
で、こっちは、結構ね、男性的、あの、すごい試みなのですが、
And this one is quite a bold, incredible endeavor,
こちら、白銀ノエルファーストアルバム「のえさんぽ」でーす！
Here is Shirogane Noel's 1st album, 'Noesampo'!
な、なんとファーストアルバム！そうなんです！
Wh-what, a 1st album! That's right!
いや、本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you all so much.
ええと、このイラストはですね、あのクスノキハルイ先生描き下ろし、そして、あの、まあこのね、デザインなんですけど、あのサクサンキューさんのデザインになっております！
Um, this illustration is newly drawn by Kusunoki Harui-sensei, and the design is by Saku-Thankyou-san!
そしてね、なんと特典にアナザージャケットカードがありますので、
And amazingly, there's an another jacket card as a bonus,
いや、ちょっと歌頑張ったんで、ぜひぜひ皆さん聴いてください！こちらぜひね、ちょっとがんば、ありがとね、ありがと！じゃあ次！
so I really worked hard on the singing, please everyone listen to it! Please check it out—thanks, thanks! Now, next!
はい、こちら！え、おさんぽノエルぬいぐるみディヤンドル衣装ver.ということで、かぶってる。
Yes, this! Um, 'Osanpo Noel Plushie: Dirndl Outfit Ver.', which she's wearing.
そうなんですよ、やっぱ牛さんがね、ちょっと今回テーマになっている、あ、違う、ヤギ、それヤギだ。ヤギなんだけど、
That's right, cows are the theme this—ah, no, a goat, that's a goat! It's a goat, but...
牛さん、そう、このね、牛さんで、やっぱ散歩ね、のえ散歩の曲を聴きながら、これ持たして、こうやってね、一緒に行けたらなと思って持っていて歩いてください。
Cow, right, with this cow, while listening to 'Noesanpo' songs, holding this and walking together—I hope you'll take it out for walks.
あ、なんか紐が、紐が入ってる。っていうことで、あ、それヤギだ、ヤギなんだよんな。
Ah, there's a strap included. Wait, that's a goat, it's a goat!
じゃあ、はい、次行きましょう！で、こちら、一緒におさんぽリバーシブルバケットハットということで、これね、そうなんです。
Well then, yes, let's go to the next! And this is the 'Let's Go on a Walk Together Reversible Bucket Hat', and this, that's right.
おしゃれだし、さっきのキービジュアルの方にも、実はかぶってたんだよね。そう、おそろっちのね、あのリバーシブルバケットハットなので、
It's stylish, and I was actually wearing it in the key visual earlier. Yes, it's a matching reversible bucket hat,
そう、なので、ま、ちょっと、ま、牛さん柄ちょっと恥ずかしいなって人は、ま、黒の方をメインにしてちょっと、ね、牛さん柄はアクセントにしたりとか、
so if you're a bit shy about the cow pattern, you can make the black side the main one and use the cow pattern as an accent,
で、もちろんね、白銀ノエル大好きって人はね、ノエルというロゴが着いた、このこっち側をぴょってね、かぶっていただければと思います。リングも付いてる！
and of course, if you're a huge Shirogane Noel fan, you can wear this side with the 'Noel' logo facing out. It even comes with a ring!
はい、ありがとうございます。では、次、ぽん！
Yes, thank you. Now, next, pom!
ということで、えっと、ま、記念日、あの誕生日記念フルセットということで、あの今回ね、あの、なんとこのセットをね、全部買ってくださった方に、あの特典、
With that said, um, the anniversary—birthday commemoration full set! And this time, um, amazingly, for those who buy this entire set, we have a bonus...
壇上を書きます！白銀ノエル直筆サイン、箱押しメッセージ入りのポストカードを、やらせていただきます！
I'll write a message! I will do a postcard with Shirogane Noel's handwritten signature and foil-stamped message!
やばい、ちょっとね、無制限なので、ちょっと頑張りますので、なんか、あの前回戦สงでちょっとね、買えなかった人もいたので、ちょっと誕生日はちょっとみんなにハッピーになってもらいたいので、全力で頑張って書きます！
Yabai, since it's unlimited, I'll do my best because some people couldn't buy it during the previous rush, so I want everyone to be happy on my birthday, so I'll write them with all my might!
うれしい、なんでうれしいて…うーん、お耳ね。
Yay—why are you happy? Um, your ears.
で、もう一つはお誕生日お礼ボイスもありますので、そちらも聴いてください！さあ、ということでぜひチェックしてください！
And another is the birthday thank-you voice, so please listen to that too! Now, with that said, please be sure to check it out!
いや、みんなありがとね、お付き合いいただきまして。
Thank you everyone for hanging out with me.
いやいや楽しかったし、美味しい年、楽しそうな年、本当に楽しかった。
It was so fun, a delicious year, a fun year, truly fun.
いや、なんか本当にね、やっぱご飯はみんなで食べたほうが美味しいので、
Yeah, truly, eating meals together with everyone is more delicious,
やっぱこう、大好きな三期生と、そしてね、ま、しっかり…（笑）…まあ、大好き、大好きな、そう、好き、あの、司会はやっぱりかなたということで、…まあみんな大好きですということで、本当にありがとー！さあ、この誕生日になりました、ありがとー！
so with my beloved 3rd gen, and... (laughs)... well, beloved, beloved, yes, favorite—the MC is Kanata after all... well, everyone is beloved, thank you so much! Now, it's my birthday, thank you!
それでは、牛丼カーニバルも聴いてねー！聴いてねー！聴いてねー！
Well then, listen to the Gyudon Carnival too! Listen to it! Listen to it!
はい、ということでみんなありがとー！バイバイン、おつまっするー！おつまっするー！おめでとう！ありがとー！おめでとー！
Yes, with that said, thank you everyone! Bye-bye, Otsumassuru! Otsumassuru! Congratulations! Thank you! Congratulations!
白銀ノエル 1st Album「のえさんぽ」
Shirogane Noel 1st Album "Noe-sanpo"